hello ladies and gentlemen
女士们先生们  你们好
I'm Luis Gomez
我叫路易斯·戈麦斯
a machine learning engineer mood industries a music discovery startup
是一名mood industries的机器学习工程师    是一家音乐探索的创业公司
and I'd like to talk to you about machine learning
我想和你谈谈关于机器学习
why it's important why we should all learn about it
为什么这很重要  为什么我们要学习它
why it's a super fun topic
为什么这是一个非常有趣的主题
and we're gonna demonstrate this using the example of speech recognition
接下来  我们会用语音识别作为例子  回答我刚刚的问题
we're gonna use some really cool machine learning algorithms today
我们将要运用一些超级酷的机器学习算法
to recognize our own speech
来识别我们自己的语音
so why machine learning why is it even important
所以为什么是机器学习？  为什么它是如此重要呢？
why should we learn about this stuff
为什么我们要学习它呢？
well according to Google CEO
谷歌首席执行官曾说过
it's more profound than electricity or like fire
机器学习比电或火更重要
and you know he's not
你知道他不是
I won't disagree with him I pretty much agree with that statement
我同意这一点  我非常赞成这一论点
machine learning is huge
机器学习是巨大的
it's an enormous step in humans capability in human technology and human tools
这是人类在科技与工具使用能力上的巨大进步
because what machine learning does essentially
因为本质上 机器学习所做的
is allow us people to save time energy and money
能为我们的节省时间 精力 以及金钱
okay the three most important resources to anybody
这三个资源对任何人来说都是非常重要的
but the plan today is
今天的计划是
we're gonna talk about what was machine learning
我们将要谈的是机器学习
we're gonna talk about the fundamentals of machine learning
我们会讨论机器学习的基础知识
that you can apply to all kinds of different tasks
我们要谈论的将适用于各种不同的任务
second we're gonna you know
其次  我们将会  你懂的
after we make you a machine learning expert
在我们教会你成为机器学习的专家后
you're gonna be able to give your own seminars on this stuff
你将能在这一领域  举办自己的研讨会
we're gonna talk about speech recognition
我们要语音识别
okay how do we apply this
我们将如何应用
these machine learning fundamentals that we know now
我们目前知道的机器学习的基本原理
into the world of audio
于音频的世界
and recognizing people's speech
并且还能识别人的讲话
so that covers two and three
所以我们刚刚讲的是第二和第三点
fourth we're gonna give you some hands-on experience okay
第四我们会给你一些实践经验  不错吧
you're gonna write your own code
你将编写自己的代码
you're gonna run and train your very own model today
今天 你将会运行和训练你自己的模型
so that's gonna be super exciting for you
所以这将是非常令人兴奋的
if you've never trained a neural network before
如果你之前从未训练过神经网络
if you've never trained machine learning model before
如果你之前从未训练过机器学习模型
you're
你将会
you're gonna get that experience today
你今天就可以体验到啦
so so that'll be a lot of fun
所以这将是很有趣的
and five I've got a little surprise for you
第五点  我会给你 一点惊喜
you got to stay tuned okay
敬请期待哈哈
you got to pay attention
你得保持注意力
because we're gonna make something totally original
因为我们会做一些完全原创性的东西
I'll leave that for later and
我会稍后再聊这个话题
finally  we're gonna wrap it all up by talking a little bit about the future
最后我们稍稍总结一些  并展望未来
and the future of machine learning
以及未来的机器学习
and why this topic will be so exciting
以及为什么这个主题会如此令人兴奋
in the next decade
在接下来的十年中
in the next 20 years
接下来的20年中
next 30 years even
甚至30年中
this topic will still be super relevant in the future
这个话题甚至会与未来也密切相关
and we'll talk about why
我们会先谈谈为何它会如此重要
so first of all let's start off with what is machine learning anyway
首先 让我们先看下什么是机器学习
well I'll let you read this quote up here
我会让你先看看屏幕上的这句话
as I talked a little bit about machine learning
在我谈到机器学习时
so with programming as we've done it for the past 30 40 50 years
正如在过去的30 40 50年中 我们对编程的研究
what we would do is we type out line by line instructions
主要是我们逐行输入指令说明
for a computer to follow
让电脑执行
the computer goes line 1 line 2 line 3 line 4 and it
电脑会从第1行 第2行 第3行 第4行
runs everything you know top to bottom
从上到下
left to right runs all your code exactly as you wrote it
从左到右 准确运行所所输入的所有代码
and you had to put in all of the logic
而你必须投入你所有的推理逻辑
all of the thinking
所有想法
that you wanted your program to accomplish
你希望你的程序能完成的一切
you had to think of before
你需要去提前思考
your computer could know how to do it
然后你的电脑才知道接下来去怎么做
machine learning is a completely different realm
但是机器学习是一个完全不同的领域
a completely different approach to programming
它与编程完全不同
where the idea is
在机器学习中
instead of us explicitly telling our computer do this instruction then do
我们不需要明确告诉我们的电脑执行这条指示
this instruction then do this instruction
然后那条指令  然后执行此操作
what we do with machine learning
机器学习是
is we tell our computer ok go in this direction
我们告诉我们的电脑走哪一条道路
you know try and do this
你懂的  尝试做这个吧
and we just feed it a bunch of data
我们只是提供了一堆数据
a bunch of examples of what we want it to do
一堆我们想要它做的例子
and the computer performs some math operations on it
然后电脑就会进行一些数学的运算
and it comes to its own conclusions
然后它就会自己得到一些结论
on how to reach its final goal
关于如何达到它自己的最终结论
so to sum it all up
所以简而言之
traditional programming we would do line by line by line
传统的编程中  我们会输入一行行的代码
the computer would read all of the instructions
计算机会读取所有的这些指令
and we had to think about all of our instructions
我们必须要去思考所有的这些指令
and explicitly program every piece of logic
并明确地编写每一条逻辑
machine learning is different
而机器学习则不同
because we can just give our computer a general direction
因为我们可以只是给电脑一个粗略的方向
and it will figure out a way
它会找到一种方法
to get to the goal that we want it to get to
到达我们要想要它达到的
all right so let's talk about
好吧 让我们来谈谈
why machine learning is an approach worth learning about
为什么机器学习是一种值得我们学习的方法
so let's say
比如说
I want to be able to tell the difference between a dog and a cow
我想要分辨出一只狗和一头牛
I want to be able to hand a picture off to my computer
我希望能够发一张照片给我的电脑
and have my computer tell me this is a dog this is a cow
然后由我的电脑告诉我这是一只狗 这是一只牛
one way you might think of doing it
你可能想到的一种方法是
is well let's just look at the colors right
让我们看看他们的颜色 是吗？
look at that
看那个
that first dog in that first image of the cow
在第一张图片中的那只狗  以及图片里的第一只牛
and you can say
你可能会说
well if there's a lot of brown in the image
如果图像中有很多棕色
that's gonna be a dog
那就是是狗呀
yeah that would work for that first example
是的  这可能适用于第一个例子
but if we look at that second column there
但如果我们看第二个栏
we see a fully brown chocolate milk bearing cow okay
这只牛则是全身巧克力棕
our program is gonna fail desperately on that
我们的计划将会完全失败
and it's gonna say that is a dog
电脑可能会认为这只牛是一只狗
so we can't use color something else
所以我们不能用颜色之类的作为区分标准
you might think of as maybe shape you know
你可能会想到形状
the that big brown bull there has these pointy horns
例如 那个大棕色的公牛有一些尖尖的牛角
as opposed to the dog which
而狗没有角
has more like closer together ears and
狗的两 只耳朵之间距离更紧
you can start getting really into the weeds with this stuff
你可以关注这些细节
and looking for certain shapes
并寻找一些特定的形状
and certain colors and certain amounts
和某些颜色以及数量
but again that's
但得强调的是
us putting every little bit of logic into our program
是我们把所有推理方法都输入我们的程序
imagine if we have a picture of a dog
想象如果我们有一张狗狗的照片
that's a little bit rotated or
这张照片角度有点歪斜或者
upside-down even or laying on its side
甚至上下颠倒  或是侧身躺下
our step-by-step instructions really any
我们的分步指令
set of step by step instructions will
一步步的说明将
never work as well as using a machine learning algorithm
永远不会让电脑学会机器学习的算法
that learns from training data
而这种算法则来自于训练数据
us trying to put individual bits of logic
我们尝试着将逻辑推理输入电脑的方法
will never work as well as
将永远不会像机器学习的方法那样运作
handing images to our computer and letting it figure out all the logic for us
将图像交给我们的电脑  让它来帮我们识别出所有的逻辑
so how does it do this
所以它是如何做到这一点的呢？
how does a computer learn
计算机要怎么学习呢？
well that's the whole field of machine learning
这就是机器学习领域的研究了
so the idea is that we get a bunch of training images
所以这个想法是  我们得到了大量训练用的图像
and we give this off to our computer
把这些图像交给我们的电脑
our computer does something called feature extraction
我们的电脑会进行名为特征提取
and what feature extraction is
所以特征提取是
is basically doing all
本质上来说
kinds of complicated math to the images that we pass it in or the data we pass it in
对我们输入的图像或者数据进行复杂的数学处理
and it breaks it down into like lines
它会将其分解为类似线条
and different curves and
和不同的曲线
sometimes colors different spacing between objects
有时候可能是不同的颜色  物体之间不同的间距
and it extracts these features
电脑会提取这些功能
so here you can see like
比如这张图里
the distance between two eyes cows would have a wider distance than dogs
奶牛的两只眼睛之间的距离比狗的会更宽
distance from tip of forehead to tip of nose
额头的距离到鼻尖的距离
things like that really really difficult features
像这一类 复杂的特征
for us to hand code
手工编码对我们来说是很困难的
this is what machine learning models can figure out for us
但机器学习的模型可以为我们识别出这些
and the way it does this again
那它是怎么做到这一点的呢
is just I just want to hammer this into your mind
我再次提出这个问题  只是我希望你们能将它牢牢住
all we're doing is
我们所要做的就是
feeding a machine learning model data
给机器学习模型提供数据
and it's doing different math operations
而电脑要做的就是进行各种数学运算
that allow it to extract these features from the data we give it
于是它能够从我们提供的数据中  提取这些特征
and it finds these patterns and features in the images
它会找到这些图片中的图案特征
that will allow it to identify it as different things
这样电脑就能识别出不同的物体的
so machine learning is super helpful
所以机器学习是非常有帮助的
in lots of different fields
在很多不同的领域都是如此
as different things you got healthcare
比如医疗保健
you've got machine learning robots that are identifying cancer
机器学习的机器人可以识别癌症
helping find deformities through x-rays
通过X射线  有助于发现畸形
all kinds of things in healthcare
以及各种各样的病症
online search makes online searches super intelligent
在线搜索  机器学习使得在线搜索非常智能化
autonomous cars
自动驾驶汽车
you've got self-driving cars
我们现在就可以买到自动驾驶汽车
every company's coming out with a self-driving car nowadays
如今几乎每家公司都推出了自动驾驶汽车
and that's all powered by machine learning
这一切都归功于机器学习
finance we've got lots
在金融领域 我们有很多
of machine learning algorithms
机器学习的算法
looking for fraudulent transactions
用于寻找欺诈性交易的人
people trying to launder money
试图洗钱的人
lots of illegal things that we don't want in the banking system
以及很多我们不希望发生在银行系统的机器上的非法行为
machine learning looks out for that security
机器学习可处于安全的目的  进行各种搜寻
speech recognition which is what we're gonna talk about today
语音识别就是我们今天所要讨论的
super excited for that
真的超级兴奋了
so machine learning has a ton of applications
所以机器学习在很多领域都这样的运用
and it works great in so many fields
并且效果都非常不错
again to help humans save energy time and money
再次强调  它可以帮助人类节约时间 精力 以及金钱
so we're gonna go on an adventure right now
所以我们现在就要开始探险啦
once I teach you about machine learning
一旦我开始教你机器学习
your mind is gonna be blown okay
你一定会刷新三观
you're never gonna be able to look at technology the same way again
你会从一个全新的角度来了解科技
because once I learned about machine learning
因为自从我学了机器学习
I was never able to look at programs the same way again
我对项目的认知就再也不和过去一样了
so I want to ask you before we jump into this
所以我想在项目之前  向你确认下
are you ready
你真的准备好了吗？
I'll take that as a yes
那我就理解成 好了 嘿嘿
so let's dive into speech recognition
让我们探索语音识别吧
now that you're all machine learning experts
既然你们现在都是机器学习的专家了
so a quick recap on the fundamentals
让我们快速回顾一下基本原理
I know you already know
我知道你已经知道了
this but it's just a good for refresher for those who don't
但对那些缺乏机器学习基本思想的同学  这这是一个很好的回顾
the basic idea of machine learning is we feed a machine learning model some training data
机器学习的基本理念是  我们提供机器学习模型一些训练数据
we go hey computer here's some data and
我们会说  嘿  计算机  这里是一些数据
we tell it what the data is
我们会告诉它这些数据是什么
maybe we want it to figure out what a dog is
或许我们想它知道狗是什么  所以我们
so we handed a bunch of pictures of a dog and
所以我们递了大量狗的图片
we say hey these are all dogs
我们说  嘿  这些都是狗狗
maybe you wanted to tell what a cow is
我想告诉我们牛是怎样的
so we handed a bunch of pictures of cows and
所以我们给了大量奶牛的照片
we say hey computer these are cows
我们说  嘿  电脑  这些都是奶牛
the machine learning model does complicated math on all the images that we give it
在我们提供的所有图片基础上  机器学习的模型会完成非常复杂的数学运算
it extracts features and looks for different patterns in the images
它会提取特征  寻找图片中的不同图案
and by doing that
这样做
it's able to tell what image is a dog
它能够区分出那张是狗的图片
what image is a cow and so on
是一只狗是什么形象是牛  等等
so that's a basic image recognition recap
所以这是基本的图像识别回顾
so speech recognition we kind of know how images work
语音识别有点类似我们所接触的图像识别
like you know we can look at something and see patterns
正如我们可以观察图像中的不同图案
and we can kind of think like okay
我们会有这样的一些想法
maybe a computer is looking for like certain
活血一台电脑正在寻找
distances on the face of something or
某物表面的一些距离
certain colors but what about speech recognition
或者某些颜色  但语音识别呢？
we're gonna talk about that
我们接下来就谈谈这个
we're gonna talk about how the computer is able to recognize our speech
我们来谈谈电脑是怎么样来识别我们的语言的
and able to classify it into different words in our very own language
并且能够把辨别我们语言中的不同词句
so speech recognition quick definition
所以语音识别的简单定义
is a machine's ability to identify spoken words
是机器识别口头语言的一种能力
so instead of just using mouse keyboard touchscreens
所以它不需要使用鼠标 键盘 触摸屏
the computer will hear our voice
计算机会听到我们的声音
and know what words were saying
并且知道是我们说的是什么意思
this is also referred to as speech to text or voice recognition
说这也被称为  语音转文本  或是语音识别
one little caveat speech recognition is different from speech synthesis
需要提醒的是  语音识别不同于语音合成
so when you're talking to like Siri
所以当你在和Siri对话时
it does both of these tasks tasks
它包括语音识别与语音合成两项任务
so when you ask Siri something
所以当你问 Siri一些事情时
that is speech recognition
这是语音识别
Siri is recognizing what you're asking it
Siri意识到你在说什么
it also does speech synthesis
然后它就会开始语音合成
speech synthesis is when it comes up with words to reply to you
当它回答你的问题时  这就是语音合成在起作用
and it comes back with that iconic Siri voice
以及Siri那标志性的声音
so it tries to put sounds to the words
所以它试图把声音转化成单词
that it's replying to you with
然后回复你的话
so two different things both audio and machine learning related
所以他们都与音频及机器学习相关  但却是两个不同的东西
but just keep in mind these are two separate areas
所以只要记住这是两个独立的领域
and today we're going to be focusing on just the recognition
今天  我们就只关注语音识别
speech recognition is everywhere
语音识别随处可见
just like we talked about
正如我们所谈到的那样
machine learning being in all kinds of industries
机器学习正出现在各种行业
speech recognition is one type of machine learning
语音识别属于机器学习
that's in all kinds of industries
而机器学习正与所有行业关联
you got Google with their home assistant
比如谷歌的家庭助理
you got Amazon with Alexa
亚马逊的Alexa
you got Microsoft with Cortana
微软的Cortana
we talked about Siri a little bit okay
以及我们刚刚提到的Siri
speech recognition is everywhere and
语音识别无处不在
it's a really great way to interact with technology
并且它是一个非常赞的科技互动方式
because humans have been using language for thousands of years
因为人类使用语言已经有上千年的历史了
we're all used to speaking with our voice
我们都习惯用我们的声音说话
and interacting with the world in that way
并且以这种方式与世界互动
so why not be able to interact with our technology that way
所以为什么不能以说话的方式与科技互动呢？
instead of having the tap and scroll and type all the time
而不是仅仅靠点击  滚动  输入
what can't we just tell our computer what we want it to do
什么我们不能告诉我们的电脑我们想要它做什么？
how do we do that you know
那我们又要怎么做到呢？
how is that even possible
而这有怎么可能呢？
well the basic idea of it is
我们的基本理念是
when we speak you may know this
当我们说话时  你可能会知道这一点
when we speak sound waves vibrate from our mouths through the air okay and it goes out
当我们说话时  声波会通过空气振动传播
and other people's eardrums are able to take in those vibrations
其他人的耳膜因此能够接受到那些震动
and understand those as words and language and sound
进而理解为不同的单词 语言 和声音
but computers don't have eardrums you know
但是你知道的  电脑没有耳膜
how how do they understand speech how do
那他们是怎么能理解我们说的话
they even hear us you know
甚至听到我们说的话呢
well there's something called
这里有一个称为
an analog to digital converter also known as ADC and
模拟数据到信号数据的转换器也被称为ADC
what this is is like your computer's eardrums
它的功能就像是电脑的耳膜一样
so what this converter allows you to do
所以转换器做的
is allows your speech waves to be heard
就是让你的声波被听到
by your computer and turned into ones and zeros
通过你的计算机  声波会变成一串以1和0组成的数字
that your computer can read easily
进而被计算机简单地读取
then we put these ones and zeros into a machine learning model
然后我们这些1和0输入机器学习的模型中
the machine learning model does all kinds of
机器学习模型会将各种各样的
complicated math into the sound signals it's getting
复杂的数学转变为他所获得的声音信号
and it extracts features in the same way
它的提取特征
that we talked about with the image recognition example of the dog and the cow
就像我们谈到的识别狗狗与奶牛的图像那样
so that's the basic idea of speech recognition
所以这就是关于语音识别的基本的理念
now let's talk a little bit more about
现在让我们来谈谈关于
a specific machine learning approach that is used a lot on sound
我们经常运用的 与语音相关的 机器学习的方法
so this is called a Convnett
这种方法被称作Convnet
also called a convolutional neural network
也称为卷积神经网络
that's the more official name for this
这是该方法更正式的名称
and the basic idea of it we've already discussed it
它的基本思路  我们先前已经提到过了
you give it some kind of data
你提供电脑一些数据
and it extracts features from that data
它会从数据中提取特征
each progressive layer is learning a different feature
从每个渐进分层的数据都是在学习一个不同的特征
so if we think of our dog and cow example
我们可以联想一下狗狗和奶牛的例子
maybe the first layer is learning something super basic
可能第一层学习的是一些非常基础的东西
like like a line
比如像一条线
like an outline of a dog or the outline of a cow
或者是狗的轮廓  或牛的轮廓
now the second layer might be learning something a little more specific
第二层则可能是在学习一些比较具体的东西
like that distance between the eyes that we saw earlier
比如我们之前看到的 眼睛之间的距离
the third layer might be even more specific
第三层可能是更具体的
like combining the distance between the eyes with a certain outline
如结合与两眼之间距离的轮廓
with the distance of the ...
以及一些距离
like the length of the nose
比如鼻子的长度
so each layer big idea here is
所以这里的每一层  它的整体思路是
each layer in a convolutional neural net
在卷积神经网络学习中的每一层
learns a different kind of feature and
都会学习到 不同类型的特征
by combining those features in different ways
通过不同的方式 组合这些不同的特征
it can then tell us what the input data was
它然后就可以告诉我们  输入的数据是什么
so with sound recognition
声音识别也是如此
we give it labeled data in the same way
以相同的方式给它标记数据
except instead of handing images of a dog
有别于直接处理狗狗的图像
we would say the word dog
我们会说这只是狗
you just label it dog
只需要把它标记为狗
so today we're gonna use the example of cat bed and happy
所以今天我们要用 cat bed 和happy的例子
so we're gonna we have a lot of different examples of these words recorded already
我们录了很多这些单词的发音例子
and they're all labeled
而且他们都被贴上了标签
so all we're gonna do is feed these into a neural network
而我们要做的就是把它们输入神经网络
so like I said we have tons of recordings
就像我们有录制了很多
we've got 1700 actually combined of people saying bed
我们实际上获得了1700个人们说“bed”这个单词的录音
people saying cat and happy
人们说cat 以及 happy
and if you want
如果你想
you can check for yourself
你还可以自己检查下
open up any of those folders and listen to any of the file
打开那些文件夹  听取任何一个文件
and you'll see they're all just recordings of people saying that word
你会发现全是人们在说同一个单词的录音
so before we get into some code
所以在我们得到一些代码之前
I want to get you a little excited about speech recognition
我来告诉你们一些有关语音识别的 令人兴奋的消息
because Google has just come out with
因为谷歌刚刚发明了一款
this insane speech recognition chatbot machine learning based technology
令人疯狂的 基于机器学习技术的聊天机器人
and I just want to play you a little clip of this video
我会给大家放一小段视频
so you can see what I'm talking about
然后你们就可以了解我所说的到底是什么了
because it is unreal what they've done  Oh No
他们所做的  简直就像是在做梦
so what you're gonna hear is the Google assistant
你将会听到的声音 来自谷歌助理
actually calling a real salon
实际上也可以称作一个真正的沙龙
to schedule the appointment for you let's listen
为你安排预约  让我们一起听听看
hello how can I help you
您好 您需要什么帮助吗?
hi I'm calling to book a woman's haircut for a client
我正在为一位女士预订做发型
I’m looking for something on May 3rd  sure give me one second
我想预订5月3日的   好的，请稍等
sure what time are you looking for well at 12 p.m.
你希望预订几点的呢  12点
it sounds so real
它听起来也太逼真了
it understands what the other person is saying to it in such a natural way
它能够以如此自然的方式  理解另一个人对它说的话
it even uses vocal fillers
它甚至会使用语气词
like um and hmm and
像嗯 ummm
really natural grammar that a human would use
以及人们生活中会使用的  非常自然的语法
so this is the future the future is now okay
所以这就是未来  未来就是现在好吗
this kind of technology is developing right now
这种技术正在发展中
and you can be a part of it
而你也可以参与其中
so let's  start off with our own speech recognizer
所以现在 我们就从自己的语音识别器开始吧
that is the end of the presentation
而这就是我的陈述说明
I hope you enjoyed it and
演讲我希望你能喜欢它
now we're gonna jump into the live coding segment
现在我们要进入现场编码的环节
and yeah this will be even more fun than the presentation we just went through
是的  这将会比比起我们的刚刚的演示文稿更有趣
so we're gonna make our very own speech recognizer
所以我们就要做自己的语音识别器啦
and if your teacher hasn't already downloaded this for you
我们自己的语音识别器  如果你的老师还没有帮你下载
go to this link right here
进入这里的链接
this github.com slash this link right here
这个github.com/这个链接吧
and go ahead and download that
进去后下载
ask your teacher if you have questions on how to download that
如果你不知道如何下载  可以问你的老师
and this is what we're gonna use
这就是我们将会使用到的
now if you can't download the code right now
如果你现在不能下载代码
I'm going to run through it
那我就快速过一遍
so you can just watch this video
所以你可以看一下这个视频
and yeah we're gonna learn regardless
是的  不管怎么说  我们要学习它
so here's a quick idea of how the code is going to run
快速地讲下这个代码是如何运行的
we're going to import packages
我们会导入组件
now what packages are our different tools that programmers use
组件就是程序会使用到的不同工具
to give other programmers functionality
从而能够给其他程序员一些功能
so one programmer has already done a lot of work on audio
所以一位程序员已经做了很多关于音频的工作
okay like turning audio into different formats that the computer read easily
比如把音频转为易读取的不同格式
and do lots of math easily
以及轻松地做大量的数学上
so he will make a package out of his programs
所以他会通过他的项目做出一个组件
and share it with other programmers to download
然后分享给其他程序员去下载
so we're gonna import those packages
所以我们会直接使用那些组件
give us a bunch of different audio and machine learning tools
而这些组件能给我们大量的音频和机器学习的工具
we're gonna set different parameters
我们将设置不同的参数
which are different like knobs and sliders
就像是一些不同的 旋钮和滑块
and things that we can mess with on our machine learning model
以及一些我们能会搞砸的一些机器学习的模型
to try and increase its accuracy a little bit
为了尝试提高其准确性
we're gonna create a model
我们要创建一个模型
and kind of and the kind of model that we're gonna be using
我们将要使用的模型有点像
is that convolutional neural net that we talked about earlier
我们之前谈论过的卷积神经网络
the Convnet for short
简称Convnet
where we've got different layers
在这一模型中 我们有不同的层次
lots of different layers and
许多不同的层次
each layer is learning a different feature of speech
每一层所学习的语言特征都是不同的
so we're gonna use a convolutional neural network model
所以我们要用卷积神经网络的模型
we're going to tell it how to train
我们将要告诉它如何训练
so this is gonna be like
这有点像
hey get these speech samples from here
嘿  从这里得到一些语音的样本吧
things like that we're gonna tell the model how to get trained
一些类似这样的事情  我们会告诉模型如何得到一些训练
and then we're going to make some predictions
然后我们会进行一些预测
we're going to record
我们会做一些录音
we're gonna speak into a microphone
对着麦克风说话
and we're gonna use our trained neural network
我们将使用我们那受过训练的神经网络
to make a prediction on the words that we're saying
对我们正在说的话进行一个预测
so this is gonna be super exciting
这么说这将会是超级令人兴奋的了
and that's the basic idea of what we're gonna do today
这就是我们今天项目中的基本理念
what's up guys
兄弟们 怎么了
I hope you're ready to jump into this live coding segment
我希望你们已经做好准备  进入这个时事编码环节
where we're going to build our very own speech recognizer
我们将要建立我们自己的语音识别器
so first of all
那么  首先
let's look at these
让我们来看看这些
packages that I talked about earlier
我之前说的组件
all of these import statements
所有这些导入的语句
these are going to be our packages
这些就是我们要用的组件
so I'm gonna run over some of the important functions in this package
所以我将要运行一些组件中的重要的功能
pre process so pre process is a file
预处理  所以预处理是一个文件
that actually comes with the code at that github link
而这实际上是一些github网页链接上的代码
that was in the presentation and
就是刚刚在演示文稿中提到过的连接
it's just a file with a bunch of different functions in it
它只是一堆有着大量不同功能的文件
that will help us assemble the data together
它可以帮助我们把数据组装在一起
to feed to our neural network
然后提供给我们的神经网络
so this get labels
所以它有标签
it gets the bed cat and happy labels from our folders
我们的文件中有着bed cat 和happy的标签
now this wave to M FCC function right here
所以这个wave到mfcc这一块代码（蓝色的） 都是在执行这个功能的
this is very important and
这是非常重要的
I'm gonna describe this in quite a bit of detail here
我会稍微详细地讲一下这一小块内容
so wave files are very common sound files
所以"wave"文件是非常常见的声音文件
so this is essentially
这是非常基本的知识点
if you remember the converter that I was talking about
如果你还记得我说的转换器
our computers ear drum equivalent that
它相当于我们的电脑耳膜
here's our sound waves and turns it into ones and zeroes
我们的声波被转成1和0的数字
wave file is just all those ones and zeros
wave文件就是由那些1和0组成的
just raw audio data
只是原始音频数据
now we could feed this into a neural network
现在我们可以把它导入神经系统
just like when we feed an image into a neural network
就像当我们把图像导入神经网络一样
we just feed the image right
我们输入的只是图像对吧？
we don't do anything to the image before we feed it into the neural network
在我们导入神经网络前我们没有对图像做任何处理
but for audio processing tasks in machine learning
但对于机器学习中的音频处理任务
it's become very common to do a an intermediary step
加入一个中间步骤是非常常见的
where we do something called we extract a feature
我们称之为提取特征
and the features that we extract from that raw audio are MFCCs
而原始音频中  我们所提取特征的就叫做mfcc
Mel-Frequency Cepstral Coefficients
全称叫做梅尔频率倒谱系数
and you don't need to know what that means
你不需要知道那到底是什么意思
but essentially it allows us to
但上它使我们能够
take this raw data that's in just one dimension
把这个只有一个维度的原始数据
and turn it into something that's in two dimensions
变成某种二维的东西
that's spaced out in a way
在某种意义上 空间是被隔开的
that it's kind of similar to the way that our human ears process audio
有点类似于我们人类耳朵处理声音的方式
so we could feed that raw audio data into our network
所以我们可以把原始音频的数据导入到我们的网络中
but transforming it into a
但将其转化为
different space where we now get time and frequency
不同空间  在这样的空间中我们有时间和频率
in something that looks like this
就像图片上的这个二维的空间
where we have time and frequency
在这里我们有时间和频率
it allows us to train the neural network a little bit faster
它会让我们训练神经网络的速度加快
and make sure that it picks up on things
确保它能够听到
that maybe a human would likely pick up
人类将可能听到的声音
when it was classifying audio
当它对音频进行分类时
so that's what the wave to M FCC function does
所以这就是wave文件中M FCC函数的功能
it transforms this raw.wave audio data into into MFCCs
他会将原始音频数据转变成mfcc
which have time and frequency
于是就拥有了时间和频率
and that allows us to save time
这就使得我们节约时间
when training our neural network
当训练我们在训练神经网络时
and M FCC's are used everywhere
并且mfcc的使用几乎随处可见
they're actually at the core of the Shazam algorithm
实际上是Shazam 算法的核心
if you've ever used that app Shazam to identify songs
如果你曾经使用过Shazam的应用程序去识别歌曲的话
um Siri uses it for speech recognition
Siri用它来进行语音识别
that was like the first version of Siri
那是Siri的第一个版本
was based all around MFCCs
完全基于MFCC设计的
so super common in the machine learning world of audio
所以这是非常常见的  在有关音频的机器学习领域
save data to array is just so that
保存数据到数组是为了
once we run all of our wave files through this function here
一旦我们用这个功能运行所有的wave文件
and get MFCCs from them
并且得到了MFCC
we can just save them onto our hard drive
我们可以把它们保存到我们的硬盘驱动器上
so that the next time we want to train a new model
以便下一次我们要训练一个新模型
we don't have to get wave files and transform them into MFCCs anymore
我们就不需要再一次将wave文件转换成MFCC了
we've already got our MFCCs on the hard-disk
我们的硬盘上已经储存了我们的MFCC
so this function is great saves us a lot of time
所以这个功能很棒  为我们节省了很多时间
yeah the rest are pretty self-explanatory
是的  其余的已经不言而喻了
load data set prepare data set
加载数据集  准备数据集
get trained test
进行训练测试
all these three functions here all that they do is get our MFCCs
所有的这三个功能  所做的就是获得我们的MFCC
and combine them with the labels
并将它们与标签结合起来
combine them with the correct labels
给他们附上正确的标签
split them up into nice little portions to feed into our neural net
再将它们拆分成一些小部分  于是便能更好地导入我们的神经网络
and that's that's all that those functions do
所有的这些功能就是实现这一目的
so most important function from this package is definitely wave to MFCC
所以这个组件中最重要的功能就是  把wave文件转化成mfcc
so yeah that's this package
这就是我们说的那个组件
and it looks like this is done running now
它看起来已经运行完成了
so here this first cell right here
所以这里的第一个单元模块
and to run these you just hold shift and enter
运行这些  你需要按住shift键和enter键
hit shift and enter it on your keyboard
按住键盘上的shift和enter键
and it will run an individual cell
它就会开始运行一个单独的单元模块
and you should see something pop up like this
你应该会看到这些东西弹出来
if you don't ask your teacher for help setting up an environment for you
如果你不向老师寻求帮助  为你设定好这些
but this is what you should see if
这是你应该会看到的情况
everything is working correctly
如果一切都正常运作的话
so all these bars are saying at the bottom here
这些底部条状代码的出现
are that you have completed saving your data to the array
意味着你已经完成保存  将数据存储成了数组
and again that function comes from right here in this package
然后再次以这个组件就开始运作啦
so we've now saved data to the array
所以我们现在已经将数据保存到了数组
we're going to call the get trained test function again from right here
我们要再次调这个  'get trained test'函数
get trained test which will split up our data set nicely
'get trained test'函数会很好地拆分我们的数据集
and give us nice even portions to feed into neural net
并能得到很合适的拆分部分提供给神经网络
one portion is gonna be really big for training the neural net
一部分非常有益于神经网络的训练集
so it learns the idea of speech and
因此它学会了语音的特征
the other is the testing set which will
另一部分是测试集
allow us to see how accurate the neural net is
它让我们看到了神经是否准确
so we've got our X_train and y_train
所以我们得到了X训练集和Y训练集
X_train will have all of those MFCCs in it
X训练包含所有的mfcc
and Y train will have all of the labels
Y数据集里是对应的所有标签
so you can imagine inside of X train we've got like MFCC 1
所以你可以想象成 在X训练集里我们有mfcc 1
and then inside of Y train we've got the label bed
然后在Y训练集里  我们有所有关于bed的标签
and then underneath that
然后在这块的下面有MFCC 2
maybe we've got MFCC 2 and the label cat
我们有mfcc 2 和cat的标签
and so on
等等
so each each entry into X train is matched up with an entry in Y train
所以每进入一个的X训练集  都会有其对应的Y训练集
and X train is going to be the MFCC or the
X 训练集就是mfcc
the representation of the audio file and
或者说它代表了音频文件
Y train is going to be the label
Y训练集将成为其对应的标签
same thing goes for X test and Y test
X测试和Y测试X也是一样的原理
X test is going to have the actual you know the data the audio data
X 测试会拥有真实的音频数据
and Y test is just going to be filled up with labels
Y测试则全部是标签
and again these test sets are for testing the accuracy at the very end
再次说明  这些测试集适用于最后准确性的测试
and the training sets are going to be for training the neural network
训练集则是用于训练神经网络
so that it can learn what speech is like
所以它就能学习言语是什么样的
so here's some settings
所以这里有一些设置
we won't go through what all of these settings mean
我们就在此一一讲述这些设置的功能意义了
but these are just settings for the neural network
所有这些设置都是为神经网络而服务的
to help us bump up our accuracy a little bit
帮助我们提高一点准确性
so you can change these around
你可以改变这些旁边的代码
you can mess with these but these are pretty good settings
也可以把他们弄乱  但这些都是非常棒的设置
that should give us pretty good accuracy right off the bed
能给提供我们相当高的关于“bed”这一词的准确度
okay so
理解了吗  所以...
get model so this is the exciting part
‘get model’  这是令人兴奋的部分
this is the actual neural network okay
这是正是的神经网络
now this this was created with a package called keras
这个组件被称作keras
which we imported from up here
是从这里被导入的
and keras is really nice
keras真的非常好用
researchers use it all the time
研究人员几乎一直在使用它
because you can make neural networks super quick
因为你可以超快速地建立神经网络
each of these model.add lines right here
每一个model.add  这几行代码
these are all adding different layers into the neural network
他们的功能是  给神经网络添加不同的层次
so just like we saw in the slides earlier
就像我们在之前的幻灯片中所看到的
right here
就是这儿
here is one layer here is another layer
这儿是一层  这儿是一层
here's another layer
这儿时另一层  这些层中的每一层都是另一层
each of these layers is created with a call to this function called model.add
每一层通过此函数创建的  被称为model.add
so you can see
所以你可以看到
we've got whole bunch of layers doing all kinds of different things
我们得到了所有的层次都是在做各种不同的事情
doing convolutions doing max pooling
卷积  最大池化
drop out  flattening
退出  flatten函数(压平多维数组至一维)
we're doing a dense layer
包括全连接层
so these these are all super technical neural network terms
所以这些都是超级的技术性的神经网络术语
that you don't need to necessarily know right now
你不需要现在就知道
but just know that each of these layers
但只要记住  所有的每一层
is helping us extract certain features
都是在帮助我们提取某些特征
helping the neural network be able to get a better idea of what sound is
帮助神经网络去更好地理解声音是什么样的
and to boil down the most important parts of those MFCCs
能够将内容  提取成mfcc这样最为重要的部分
to allow it to recognize the words that they represent
进而能够识别这些词所代表的意思
this code to model.compile right here
这里的model.compile这一行
kind of glues all of these layers together
有点像胶水  能将所有这些层粘在一起
so that they can work cohesively and
所以他们可以一起协作
so that math can flow through each layer in a regular way
所以数学可以  以一种常规的方式计算每一层
and this little metrics right here is telling the neural network to
而这里的‘metrics’参数  正告诉神经网络
hey make sure you keep track of the accuracy while we're training you
嘿 当我们在训练你的时候  你要确保准确性
so cool so here is all of our model stuff
所以非常炫酷了 这里的就是我们所有模型的内容
and at the very end we're just going to return it
在最后时我们还是要将它归还
so we spit out that model to whoever calls this get model function
我们把这个模型  还给那个调用模型函数的人身上
we make a predict function
我们会制作一个用于预测的函数
so this is going to be a way that will call the predict function
所以它会调用预测功能
we're gonna record ourselves saying some piece of audio
我们要记录自己说话的一些音频
and we're gonna call the predict function and
然后我们就要调用预测函数
point it to that piece of audio and
并将它用于那段片段的音频
also we're gonna give it a trains machine learning model
同样  我们要给它一个训练的机器学习模型
so that's how the predict function is gonna to work
这就是预测函数的运作方式
but just know so this predict function is going to take in a file
但只用知道这个预测函数只用接收文件
it's going to get that file
它会接收到那个文件
get that raw audio
得到原始的音频
extract MFCC's from it and
从中提取出mfcc
then it's going to pass it into the neural network
然后它会将mfcc传递到神经网络
to get a prediction on what the machine learning model thinks that it is
在机器学习的模型上  获得它所预测的意思
I'm flipping back and forth between
我一直在来回
saying neural network and machine learning model
解释神经网络和机器学习的模型
in this case they're both the same
在这种案例中  它们是相同的
machine learning models don't have to be neural networks
机器学习模型不一定非要是神经网络
there are other kinds of machine learning models
这里还有其他类型的机器学习的模型
but I'm just kind of flipping back and forth between them
但我经常来回在使用两个术语
because this is just generally
因为这只是
we're talking about machine learning today
我们今天所谈的机器学习
but this is a convolutional neural network that we're working with today
也就是我们今天在运用的卷积神经网络
so now it's time to build the model and train it
所以现在是时候建立模型  并且训练它了
so we've got we saw that get model function earlier
所以我们之前已经得到了模型函数了
it's building up all these layers
它正在建立所有的这些层级
now we're actually going to call it
现在我们要开始调用它们了
and we're gonna store it into this variable right here
我们要将其存储为变量
called model
在这里被命名为 model（模型）
and then we're gonna call the fit function on that model that we just built up
然后我们会把刚刚建立的模型称之为fit函数
and we're gonna train it using our X train that we talked about
我们会用刚刚谈到的X训练集  来训练它
which is all the audio data all the MFCCs
它包含了所有MFCC
Y train which has all the labels to all of the MFCCs
Y训练集  则具有所有的mfcc的标签
here are some of the
这里是一些
settings that we talked about earlier
我们前面谈到的设置
and then validation data is going to be our test
然后将测试这些数据
so this is how we're gonna check our accuracy
这是为了检测我们的准确性
and X test is a
X测试集是包含
smaller set of the audio of the MFCC samples
MFCC音频集的其中一部分样本
and Y test is a smaller set of the labels
Y测试集是Y训练集中的一部分标签
so and remember every item in X train
并记住X训练集中的每一部分
is matched up to its correct label in Y train
都有其Y训练集中  对应的正确的标签
same with X test and Y test
X测试和Y测试也是相同的道理
so we're gonna run this
所以我们要开始运行这个啦
we're gonna start training
开始训练啦
let's go wow that looks terrifying man
开始吧！  哇  这看起来有点恐怖
it's training pretty quick
它训练的速度非常快
so trainings going to take a while
所以训练将需要一段时间
I'll let you ask your teacher questions if you have any
如果你有问题  你可以现在问问你的老师
you can just appreciate how beautiful the training looks
你也可以欣赏下训练的壮观场景
yeah I'm gonna take a little break
我们会稍稍休息下
I'm gonna let this train for a little bit
我会它训练一会儿
and I'll be right back
我会马上回来的
alright so it looks like my model is done training
好吧  看起来  我的模型已经完成训练啦
and I actually came up here
我实际是从这里开始的
and I lowered my epochs this
我降低了我的epochs（次数）
used to be 50 I just brought that down to 20
它本来是50  我刚刚往下调到了20
and what an epoch is is every time
epoch指的是每一次
that your neural network has seen every sample in your training set
你的神经网络遍历训练集中的每个样本
once that's an epoch
一次 这就是一个epoch（次数）
so that used to be 50 before and you can imagine
所以它本来是50  你可以想象
seeing every single piece of training data
每看一条训练数据
doing all kinds of math you know
就意味着它完成了各种各样的数学计算
it's going through all these layers that
也就是说 他会经历所有这些层次
we defined earlier and it's doing all kinds of math
而这些层次就是我们早先定义的  它正在做各种各样的数学运算
going through all these layers
经历所有这些层级
50 times for every single sample
每一个样本查看50遍
it's gonna take a long time to train
要花很长时间训练
so to speed that up I lowered my epochs to 20
所以为了加速  我把epoch次数降到了20次
and you can do the same
而且你可以这样做
just know that this will it'll be a little bit less accurate
但要知道  这其实会略微降低它的准确性
but I think it'll still be good enough to recognize voice
但我认为它还是能够较好地识别声音的
so I'm going to record myself saying the word happy
所以我要去 记录自己的声音  我会说happy这个词
and I'm going to save that to a .wave file
我会把它保存到.wave的文件里
and I'm gonna put it in here and
我要把它放在这个位置
try and run a prediction on it
尝试着预测它
to see what our neural network thinks that I said
来看看我们的神经网络认为我说的会是什么
so here we go happy
那么我们开始吧  HAPPY
you don't need to say that you don't need to use a full on microphone
你不一定要使用全向麦克风 说这个词
you can just say it into your computer microphone
你可以就对着你电脑的麦克风说
and it should be good enough to understand what you just said
去理解你所说的话  电脑麦克风的效果也会很不错的
so let's let's try this out yeah oh
让我们试试吧  哇哦！！  yeah~~
that's so cool that was so fast - Wow happy
这也太酷了吧  并且还很快 - 哇 Happy
there's there's your prediction
那是电脑给的预测答案
that's awesome
这简直太棒了
always man
兄弟  总是着这样的
every time new neural networks never failed to amaze me
神经网络每一次都让我感到十分震惊
I'm still like a little kid around them
每次围在它旁边  我都想是一个小孩子
so there you go we trained our own super basic
所以我们训练了一些非常基础
but still really cool speech recognizer
但仍然非常酷的语音识别器
and yeah you can examine this code
是的  你可以检查一下这个代码
this is a good stepping stone
这是一个很好的跳板
for you to learn more about neural net works
你可以进一步去学习神经网络是如何运作的
and machine learning in general
以及机器学习
so I hope you enjoyed that little demo and
所以我希望你会喜欢那个小小的演示
I hope you enjoyed this presentation
我希望你能享受这次的分享
my name is Luis with Palo Alto Education
我是来自Palo Alto Education的路易斯·帕洛阿尔托
and I will see you guys later bye
我们以后再见  Bye